hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft as you
can see i'm chilling in my little
relaxation area because i've basically
been away for a week as i said in my
last episode
and that didn't actually stop me doing
some work in in the few hours that i was
home and able to do something i was
doing something but i'm now back at it
and it is time to get started so time to
get these little fellas off of my
shoulders and go and hop back into work
straight away
i i practiced that
so much
i practiced
pulling up at the last second
and yet when it comes to actually
recording i
mess it up
unbelievable you know there's not really
a way into my base if i don't respawn
inside my base there's not a wave but
fortunately because i've been
transporting some villagers i actually
created this little walkway which is
very very handy thanks to iskal i
actually have a villager ready to go
into the system you know what that was
so embarrassing i want to try it again i
don't i don't want it to end like oh
look at that yep
typical typical typical right let's do
it again
but this time i'm going to show you how
it was really supposed to go so let's
jump back into things yeah let's do it
again look this is how it was supposed
to go you meant to pull up at the last
second
and then just float down i do that so
many times but the one time i record
anyway last episode i was completing the
pate tube now i've actually got my hands
on some farmers they are in there doing
doing all the farming and it wasn't
actually mumbo that gave them to me in
the end he couldn't get many farmers but
iskall also has one and he has provided
me with lots of brown coats so basically
these guys have been really really
productive there's a lot of potatoes and
carrots coming down the system now i was
thinking i can produce some kind of like
mini emerald farm so for that i'm gonna
need some more farmers it's actually
really cool to see this how it works
like it it basically pumps them all the
way down these guys collect it and they
just send it on their way so it's like
these guys are all working together to
send down
all of the potatoes into here but i do
need to actually create some more space
anyway let's send in our first trader
shall we
so
oh no
he was right here
i was saving him i had him ready i was
gonna call him bill i even had a name
tag for him
ah
i
must have i left a space open here and
he's gone in that time this is really
tragic like he's just left an empty
minecart he was right here i swear i
left him i'm actually a little bit upset
here i i was i enjoyed his company
anyway ugh we're gonna have to go and
get another one from iskall's base
for those of you wondering about my
missing trident from the live stream yep
we went and did some end raiding and
stuff and i threw my trident into the
void like an
idiot i've got the trident back but it's
it's not quite the same it was very
stupid of me
okay so i've got some here thanks to
iskal i actually have a bunch of these
guys
so this one is the actual farmer this is
the one we're going to take with us on a
journey
looks like he's like
properly looking into the ocean
i'm taking him on a tour of hermitcraft
through the ice bill we go and on your
right you'll see stress monster's castle
founded at the beginning of the season
and is continually being worked on to
this day
and if you look to the left you will see
some polar bears in their natural
habitat it's floating
and on your left you will see the random
crafting table a staple product of the
hermitcraft server where people don't
clean up after themselves
absolutely disgraceful
and straight ahead you will see the
beginnings of the futuristic east line
part of the hermitcraft rail network due
to be completed
sometime in the far future
this is pretty cool actually it feels it
feels odd to give a tour and we're
nearly there and if you would look
straight ahead you will see the best
base on the hermitcraft server no i'm
kidding i'm kidding it is a pretty cool
base though and i'm pretty happy that
it's nearly finished all right bill
we're going straight in
there we go i really hope you're still
back there bill
yeah okay good uh for some reason we're
now under bill please tell me you're not
drowning bill please do not start
drowning
the titanic is sinking all right let's
get you out of there bill and let's get
you on to a minecart
there we go and he's in hey guys i've
prepared a villager i totally didn't
mess up the first time right let's send
him down into his little trading slot
and
timber
and now i can trade with this guy at
will so i basically grab some potatoes
and carrots and if i have enough of
these guys
i can basically just get unlimited
emeralds
or at least a lot of emeralds so i might
actually because of the carrots and the
potatoes they're gonna max out really
quickly so to make this more efficient i
should really create a small but
efficient pumpkin and melon farm to make
this work
and of course his name is going to be as
devastating as the other ones we've got
garroth uh eater of worlds we've got
like balrok or welding you know stuff
like that this guy's gonna have an
equally awful name
bill
destroyer of my last name tag
oh no no no no no no
how how how did you get in here i don't
worry bill i got your back but i'm not
sure where that zombie just came from i
think i'm gonna safely lock these guys
away pretty sure that nothing should get
to these guys but just in case
i think we gotta seal this off down here
but just to be on the safe side i'm
going to need isgal to provide me a few
more farmers also guys you weren't
supposed to tell him about the iskall
architect lol
give me a chance to send it myself he's
been asking me on the side you know he's
like hey green what's what is what is
iskout architect lol and i'm like
it's nothing
come on guys i need i can't really i
can't come up with a good excuse just
give give me a moment and we'll we'll
invite him in our own way don't you
worry about that now today i've not just
been filling up the potato with world
eaters and world destroyers and bill i
have actually
worked on and finished the majority of
the architect
train station platform which i'm really
really excited to show you so here's a
little time lapse of how that went down
so basically let's kick this off with
how it all went down
i started by forgetting to press f1 now
this footage is particularly interesting
because i then shaved off that entire
island and lowered it a few blocks below
sea level however
during this recording my cat my dearly
beloved maui decided he was going to
walk all over my keyboard and this is
what it looks like when your cat walks
on your keyboard it just descends into
the void and fortunately i realized and
was able to bring it back so i've got
myself a little underwater island and it
actually took a really long time to do i
agreed with mumbo to get rid of that
island so no worries there was no plans
for it and it was kind of in the way so
i decided that i was going to cover it
in sand and actually make it look
somewhat nice even if it does stand out
just a little bit then i got going on
the actual platform now i wanted to keep
this super simple so i went for an
obvious shape and kept it within the
cyan terracotta the white concrete and
the cyan glass theme that i've got going
on between mine and mumbo's base
so i also wanted to try and theme it
architect because obviously the two
members of architect mumbo and myself
are the only people that this platform
services so i decided to just make it
all to do with that so i created this
weird egg shape with glass so you can
see through the bottom
and then i just added a giant a which i
have actually typified by putting a bit
of sea lanterns in the middle and then a
quartz a of some kind it kind of varies
on depending on the size of the a but
overall i think this has ended up
looking really quite nice i did have to
make it oddly thick for it to work and
then i gave it a little bit of detail
around underneath and then it was done
and after i finished the platform so i
basically removed that island created
the platform created the giant architect
logo i think that this
looks really really cool and from the
air if you take a substantial leap
backwards and you like admire this whole
thing in the setting it looks really
really cool i think it fits in with both
mine and mumbo wait no mine and mumbo's
base
however
people will say undoubtedly that it
looks like it's not in the middle it
looks like it's closer to mumbo's base
than it is to mine it's not it just
looks that way because my base i counted
the outside of my base to be this outer
ring here and not the bit in the middle
and i counted the outside of mumbo's
base to be just on the outside of that
ring there so just because of the way
that our bases are
it looks like it's closer to mumbos but
it's actually directly in the center of
the two bases which is um what i meant
about mathematically correct but
visually incorrect
so it's it's not moving it's far too
late for that and it also gives me
another thing to fly through
so i've also created the actual lines
and you can see here i've been counting
out the way i um actually created some
support beams a few designs but i've
settled on
an altogether more simpler one just a
very simple like y shape and it's got
quite annoyingly a two block center
basically because i went mathematically
correct on the center of the platform
it had a two block center between mine
no mine and mumbo's bases so
yeah it's got a two block center which
is different from all the other parts of
the network but i thought it was about
time to actually get this
finished because i've been threatening
to do this for a long time but i've kept
it nice and simple as i really planned
to but i think it's also in theme
and it works really well and there's
also the option to continue it
all the way onwards to x's base which is
somewhere over here with a geometrical
themed base either way i'm very happy
with how this project's gone and this
actually looks really cool it took a
long time to
uh actually make this island work but
after terraforming it i was actually
gonna make it like coral reef but just
because the water is deep ocean it
didn't really look right
in other news i've also created my
second did you die box all the way
finished and i'm work now working on my
third so it's it's getting there it's
just you know it's a very expensive
process and look at the multi-colored
mess of shulker boxes
honestly
at this point unless somebody is going
to make me a sorter
this isn't going anywhere i have i have
at least put sand in the yellow shulker
boxes but that's because that's going to
be
for a different project
but either way i'm going to quickly i've
just seen a
mistake in that and it's bugging me
already i've missed a block but i'm
going to basically finish off all of
these supports and get this done now
this here i've been wondering what this
mystery
square of glass has been for a long time
this is actually the east station in the
hermitcraft rail network which i did not
know now that that's done
mumbo and i can actually work on
the project that we had a meeting about
which is
actually not going to be called amazon
now i actually read a lot of your guys's
suggestions now a couple of people only
two i must have had
several thousand suggestions a lot of
them were like hermits on or hermitcraft
zone something like that but a couple of
people said sahara because you know it's
the amazon rainforest and it's the
sahara desert so they're kind of like
you know opposites in a way but on the
same line of thinking so
this project is officially going to be
called the sahara project or just sahara
for sure i think this is going to be
excellent and you can see there's a
couple of red
terracotta here and you can see it marks
out
a big square
right here and then the rail network
goes around it that's because this is
going to be
where the sahara headquarters
is going to be made
and there's even more space over here as
well and it's all going to be linked up
and end up
right here
at the shopping district now this is
technically the futuristic district
but
the
problem is nothing's really been built
here the two people that are building in
the futuristic district are in the ocean
so i don't actually know what the style
of this whole thing will actually look
like
the only person living here
is tfc
and his house hasn't changed since day
one it's even got a green head hunt
green head on it
so yeah this is this hasn't changed
since day one this is tfc's vault
so i'm not actually sure what this is
going to look like i'm going to have to
do some major
major experimentation and i'm gonna have
to consult with mumbo but i think the
first thing that we're gonna have to do
is invite iskall and that i think we'll
have to wait to the next episode and
after a little bit of work i have added
every single pillar in here now i
actually really think that the spacing
here is okay i was gonna have double the
amount you can see that little marker
right there but i think it would be way
too cluttered especially given like how
much open space there is between my base
mumbo's base and the platform but i
think that this looks pretty good even
if it doesn't actually match up with the
rest of the rail network so all there is
left for me to do is to remove all of
this sand over there and over here and
then i think we will be able to tell ren
that our job here is done
whoa
sorry
what the heck was that
wait where did it go
no where did it
where did it go
what was that
what
sorry i am the only person online i
can't believe i missed that i couldn't
see it because i fell off the rail no
i have got i've gone off the rail guys
it's just a pickle here what on earth
was that either someone's playing a
really dirty trick on me or it was just
a mob that had
never why would the mob be invisible
i mean that's really really weird
i
i'm really really freaked out actually
what on earth well either way
we are now completely finished with this
part of the line actually i need to go
and fix that over there because i need a
few more rails to finish this off so now
that the track is actually built i do
actually need to add some more things
unfortunately because i need to power
the rails and this is actually the red
district line so ren told me that i have
to include some kind of red into it
so i was thinking what i could do
is perhaps either side of
these pillars i could add some redstone
blocks some panes to connect them up and
this will add the dash of red that ren
says i need to have in order for this to
be you know
labeled correctly on the right district
line because they're all color coded
apparently which i didn't actually
realize and then i just put loads of
powered rails along here let's actually
go and take a look how that looks
it's not as clean but it does actually
work and it will give it that dash of
red that it desperately requires
and i've added all of the powered rails
now all the way along it adds that
splash of red that ren wanted
i think he can't really complain i guess
i'll go and let him know that that's now
finished and he can inspect it in his
own time
but for now i think i've got to give it
at least one test just to make sure that
it works
so mumbo's already said that he's going
to be doing all of the technical stuff
here to make it stop start when we want
it's probably not exactly fine
but probably barely five minutes of work
there
definitely less than building this whole
thing however i just wanted to make sure
that this works
so it powers it does it give you enough
oomph to get to the next one just about
man these powered rails really don't do
an awful lot do they i may need to add
more in here because this is
slow or maybe i'm just used to traveling
really really fast
i suppose it's meant to be nice and
therapeutic to be honest with you
oh yeah i forgot there's no there's no
end
green
sitting on the sea floor
no no don't worry no more songs no more
songs
and now we can finally move on with
project sahara but i think that's
probably all that i have time for today
so basically i've got back from my week
away in norway
and i have got back and jumped straight
into it by building the architect
platform and part of the rail network
and i have got some villagers in my
potato and we saw a very weird
pickle related incident i guess i think
a mob was probably invisible somehow and
just was
chilling but
i really don't i literally am the only
person online so i don't understand at
all i've got my trading villages here
bill uh you don't have a name yet you
know what in the comments let me know
who this guy is or girl what who is this
what's their name what's their story
where where have they been
and i am actually accumulating a bunch
of emeralds having spent
the three stats that impulse gave me and
i'm slowly accumulating all of this so
basically just take all this pass it
over to bill he passes me the money job
done bingo bango we're pretty rich
okay so thank you very much for watching
everyone i hope you enjoyed this episode
sorry it's a little bit slower i am
definitely getting back into things now
and hopefully we'll have the next
episode ready for you very very shortly
okay good
bye